<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<assessment-results
    uuid="a7cb1d85-bb05-49ab-acc4-074b5711736b"
    xmlns="http://csrc.nist.gov/ns/oscal/1.0">
    <metadata>
        <title>CSA SignServer Pre-Authorization Assessment Report</title>
        <last-modified>2024-01-20T13:57:28.355446-04:00</last-modified>
        <version>1.0</version>
        <oscal-version>1.0.4</oscal-version>
        <role id="assessor">
            <title>CSA SignServer Assessor</title>
        </role>
        <party uuid="5426fcf0-212a-4d4c-be67-f023c7e2370c" type="person">
            <name>Joana Sousa</name>
            <member-of-organization>889ce9bd-6a5c-4298-806f-b9a50a8348b8</member-of-organization>
        </party>
        <party uuid="889ce9bd-6a5c-4298-806f-b9a50a8348b8" type="organization">
            <name>Chrono Secure Agency</name>
            <short-name>CSA</short-name>
        </party>
        <responsible-party role-id="assessor">
            <party-uuid>5426fcf0-212a-4d4c-be67-f023c7e2370c</party-uuid>
        </responsible-party>
    </metadata>
    <import-ap href="./ap.oscal.xml"/>
        <local-definitions>
        <activity uuid="629e3e65-a99a-46f3-aa9e-46c544e9f394">
            <title>Examine System Elements for Secure Digital Signing and Timestamping</title>
            <description>
                <p>The activity and its steps will be performed by the assessor and facilitated by the owner, ISSO, and product team for the CSA SignServer system with necessary information and access about the secure design and implementation of the system's elements.</p>
            </description>
            <prop name="method" value="EXAMINE"/>
            <step uuid="d32ab484-14ac-4540-9e43-91788aeb61be">
                <title>Review System Configuration</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will review the system configuration settings and documentation for the SignServer application, DSS Framework, and related components. This step addresses potential misconfigurations that could be exploited.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>The system configuration settings and documentation were thoroughly reviewed, ensuring all components are correctly configured to prevent potential misconfigurations.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="e4a04c6d-4bb7-4d67-a8fc-9d0c69e65eec">
                <title>Verify Secure Key Management</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will verify that the HSM is correctly integrated and configured for secure key management. This ensures that cryptographic keys are protected against unauthorized access and theft.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>The HSM integration and configuration were verified to ensure cryptographic keys are securely managed and protected from unauthorized access.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="d83cbd22-0e6c-4082-b7ce-89a01c96028a">
                <title>Test Timestamp Accuracy</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will test the accuracy and integrity of timestamps generated by the SignServer. This step addresses vulnerabilities related to incorrect or tampered timestamps.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>Timestamp accuracy and integrity were tested, confirming that timestamps are generated correctly and are resistant to tampering.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="caab6a17-17f6-4fa1-9475-aac08d909a7f">
                <title>Examine Access Control Implementation</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will examine the implementation of access controls, ensuring that only authorized personnel can perform signing and timestamping operations. This addresses potential privilege escalation and unauthorized access.</p>
                </description>
            </step>
            <related-controls>
                <control-selection>
                    <include-control control-id="au-8"/>
                </control-selection>
            </related-controls>
            <responsible-role role-id="assessor">
                <party-uuid>5426fcf0-212a-4d4c-be67-f023c7e2370c</party-uuid>
            </responsible-role>
            </activity>
    </local-definitions>
    <result uuid="a88c8d43-0271-4dd8-87c8-b2bec0734e41">
        <title>CSA SignServer Pre-Authorization Assessment Result 1</title>
        <description>
            <p>This will be the first result once the assessor has completed their final analysis in the assessment.</p>
        </description>
        <start>2024-06-25T15:35:28.355446-04:00</start>
        <reviewed-controls>
            <control-selection>
                <include-control control-id="au-8"/>
            </control-selection>
        </reviewed-controls>
    <observation uuid="0764b173-d97a-4417-b498-658e50e9f387">
            <title>Keyfactor SignServer HSM Key Protection Assessment</title>
            <description>
                <p>Assessment of the HSM integration for Keyfactor SignServer to ensure secure key storage and compliance requirements.</p>
            </description>
            <method>EXAMINE</method>
            <type>control-objective</type>
            <subject subject-uuid="35d1c6d4-164c-4095-ac58-80994b888d59" type="component"/>
            <collected>2024-06-25T20:13:11.355446-04:00</collected>
            <remarks>
                <p>While Keyfactor SignServer is configured to use an HSM for key storage, analysis of system logs indicates that some timestamp signing operations were executed using software-based key stores.</p>
                <p>This deviation suggests either misconfiguration or fallback behavior where certain requests are handled outside of the HSM environment.</p>
                <p>The absence of strict enforcement of HSM usage could expose timestamping keys to unauthorized access, increasing the risk of key compromise.</p>
            </remarks>
        </observation>
                <risk uuid="5bf9a3c6-6e52-4416-bef2-42a7a57b37b5">
            <title>Unauthorized Access to Timestamp Signing Keys</title>
            <description>
                <p>If an attacker or unauthorized user gains access to the signing keys used for timestamping operations, they could issue fraudulent timestamps, compromising the integrity and trust of signed documents and software.</p>
            </description>
            <statement>
                <p>Failure to properly secure and restrict access to the timestamp signing keys can lead to unauthorized issuance of timestamps, potentially allowing adversaries to backdate or forward-date signatures on critical documents or software.</p>
                <p>Such a compromise could undermine regulatory compliance (e.g., eIDAS, RFC 3161, FedRAMP) and expose organizations to legal and financial penalties. If exploited, this risk could also erode trust in the organization's timestamping authority, leading to reputational damage and loss of business.</p>
            </statement>
            <status>investigating</status>
        </risk>
        <finding uuid="47f8714b-bd59-4f2e-9b0a-5b0ae99024b5">
            <title>Timestamp Signing Keys Not Protected by HSM</title>
            <description>
                <p>The assessor identified that the timestamp signing keys used by Keyfactor SignServer are stored in software-based key stores instead of a Hardware Security Module (HSM). This configuration does not align with best security practices, including FIPS 140-2 Level 3 compliance.</p>
                <p>The SSP (System Security Plan) states that all cryptographic keys should be securely stored within an HSM to prevent unauthorized access. However, the assessor was able to confirm that the private key used for timestamping remains accessible within the filesystem, exposing it to potential compromise.</p>
            </description>
            <target type="objective-id" target-id="au_8">
                <description>
                    <p>This is a finding.</p>
                </description>
                <status state="not-satisfied"></status>
            </target>
            <implementation-statement-uuid>76133e90-c573-43bb-aaf9-684eb00ec351</implementation-statement-uuid>
            <related-observation observation-uuid="0764b173-d97a-4417-b498-658e50e9f387"/>
            <associated-risk risk-uuid="5bf9a3c6-6e52-4416-bef2-42a7a57b37b5"/>
        </finding>
    </result>
</assessment-results>